# **Tyler Burleigh**

linkedin.com/in/tylerburleigh github.com/tylerburleigh tylerburleigh.com

I'm a data scientist with a unique background in human psychology. I have extensive experience working with product teams to make better decisions through metrics, experiments, and quantitative user insights. I am proficient with statistical/ML modeling, causal inference, data visualization, and designing ETL pipelines.

### **Education**

•	PhD, Applied Cognitive Science, University of Guelph, Canada	2011 - 2017
•	Master of Arts, Psychology, Carleton University, Canada	2009 – 2011
•	Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (CS Minor), Bishop's University, Canada	2005 - 2009

## **Work Experience**

#### Data Scientist / Data Scientist II

**Prodigy Education** 

Iun 2020 - Present

Educators product team

Toronto, Canada

- Designed robust ETL pipelines for core product analytics using SQL and dbt
- Developed a self-serve experiment analysis tool for product teams using SQL & Python that performs frequentist and Bayesian hypothesis tests, reducing the data team's experiment workload by 25%
- Used quasi-experimental methods like difference-in-difference to evaluate several product releases, reducing time-to-market by more than 50% compared to experimental methods
- Developed an ML pipeline to predict user activation using logistic regression and random forest models which achieved 74% balanced accuracy, generating key insights into user funnel optimization
- Led a small team to engineer and evaluate prompts for a new "math tutor" product application using the latest generative AI / LLM technologies like GPT-4

Nov 2018 - Mar 2020 **Data Scientist Clover Health** 

Behavioural Science team

New Jersey, US

- Designed, instrumented, and analyzed over 25 behavioral science health interventions
- Worked with product teams to implement high-impact interventions at scale by developing algorithms to identify intervention-eligible customers, and metrics and analytical designs to evaluate impact

**Research Scientist Datacubed Health** Jan 2018 - Nov 2018

Measurement and Technology team

New York, US

- Worked with mobile app team to develop and validate neurocognitive assessments like the Flanker, Stroop, and N-back tasks that would be consistent with "gold standard" versions found in the research literature
- Developed web versions of these same cognitive assessments using HTML, JavaScript, and R that could be administered online via Amazon's Mechanical Turk
- Conducted research to empirically cross-validate mobile and web versions

#### **Asst. Research Scientist**

#### **New York University**

Mar 2017 - Dec 2017

Measurement and Technology team

New York, US

Managed the selection, implementation, and validation of 100+ mobile psychological assessments

# **Projects**

pyMturkR **Sept 2019** 

- Developed an R package for the AWS MTurk API to streamline workflows for online researchers
- Technologies used: R, Python, AWS

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: R, Python, SQL
- **Libraries**: tidyverse, tidymodels; numpy, pandas, statsmodels, sklearn
- Technologies: Databricks, Snowflake, Sisense, Segment, dbt